▍2026 国家银行公开赛（多伦多）1/8 决赛
亚历山德罗娃 7-6(3) 4-6 6-4 萨巴伦卡 · 赛后场上采访
There were a lot of twists
这一路起起伏伏
and turns along the way.
波折不断
What ultimately turned in your favor
最终是什么帮你翻了盘
to close it out there in the third set?
让你拿下第三盘
What was the difference?
关键的不同在哪儿
Um, honestly, I don't know.
说实话 我也不知道
Um, I just tried to play every single point
我只是尽量把每一分
as it was the last one
都当成最后一分打
because with her like you you didn't get
因为对她 你不会有
a lot of uh chances during the matches
太多机会
but I had a lot today but I couldn't realize all
今天我拿到不少 但没能
of them but honestly I was like I
全部把握住 但说实话 我
was trying not to think
尽量不去想
about you know about the score
关于比分
about like anything just you know hit
什么都不想 就是打球
the ball and that's it.
仅此而已
But I'm super happy that I could win
我特别开心能赢下这场
because after I don't know
因为打完
after second set I thought I
第二盘打完的时候
so it's already passed me.
我以为机会已经溜走了
Well you this was your 10th career meeting
这是你们生涯第十次交手
with Aryna.
和萨巴伦卡
You're familiar. You're now dead even five
你很了解她了 现在战绩追平
wins each.
五比五
How much did that steal your confidence
这给了你多少信心
to know that you could kind
让你觉得能
of get her off her rhythm?
打乱她的节奏
Oh, well, I mean, I don't know if I
这个嘛 我说不好是不是
could get her the rhythm because I mean,
真打乱了她的节奏
she played great and um I don't know,
因为她打得很好 我也说不好
maybe I was, you know, some lucky
可能有几个球
and some shots and honestly, I don't know,
我运气不错吧 说实话
but I'm super happy with that result
但我对这个结果特别满意
because beating number one,
因为赢下世界第一
it's, you know, it always feels nice
感觉总是很好
and um I will just enjoy tonight.
今晚我就好好享受
Absolutely, you should.
没错 你应该好好享受
And Ekaterina,
叶卡捷琳娜
this is your first 1,000-level quarterfinal
这是你首次打进千分级八强
since February of 2025.
自2025年2月以来
What has that journey been like
这一路你是怎么熬过来
in the in between for you and what makes
这场胜利对你来说
that so special this win?
为什么这么特别
I mean it it means a lot
这对我意义重大
because after you know um a lot of struggle
因为经历了很多挣扎
on the court I'm just uh super happy
在场上 我现在特别高兴
that I you know can enjoy tennis.
能重新享受网球
I can enjoy my time on the court
能享受在场上的时光
because there is some difficult moments
因为之前有过一些艰难时刻
and there's no happiness on the court
那时候在场上完全没有开心
with for me but now I feel great
可言 但现在我感觉很棒
and thank you guys.
谢谢大家
The atmosphere was amazing tonight.
今晚的氛围太棒了
So I'm just enjoying.
我就是在享受这一切
Well, you're in newfound territory
你打进了从没到过的领域
into the quarterfinals here
八强
at the National Bank Open.
国家银行公开赛
Good luck, Ekaterina.
祝你好运 叶卡捷琳娜
Thank you so much.
非常感谢